再说一次
Once again,
我非常感激三位抽出宝贵时间
I'm most grateful you have given me your precious time
听我详细介绍我的职业
so that I may explain a little more about my profession
及其对贵团体诸位女士的潜在吸引力
and how it may interest the ladies of your group.
■
本字幕由
ShinY深影字幕组
原创译制
深影字幕组论坛
http://shinybbs.vip
这不是个团体 斯嘉丽小姐
It is not a group, Miss Scarlet.
团体这个词 既不能表示我们的成员目的
Group is a noun that conveys neither the purpose
也不能表示我们的成员质量
nor the quality of our membership.
我们是一个文化协会
We are a cultural society,
布卢姆斯伯里女子文化协会
The Bloomsbury Ladies Cultural Society.
■
|
注意到了 帕克夫人
Duly noted, Mrs Parker.
就像我说的那样
As I was saying,
我很乐意给贵协会做一次演讲
I would like to give a lecture to your cultural society,
揭示私人侦探的迷人世界
revealing the fascinating world of the private detective.
把我案件簿里的故事活灵活现地呈现出来
Brought to life with stories from my own casebook.
我的目的是激励诸位女士
My intention is to inspire your ladies.
我不是自吹自擂
I don't wish to sound boastful,
但我是伦敦唯一的女侦探
but I am the only female detective in London.
这无疑决定了你的客户质量
Which is no doubt the reason for the calibre of your clients.
我的客户质量
The calibre of my clients?
据我们所知
It is our understanding
雇你的都是些绝望并且贫困的人
that you are engaged by the desperate and impoverished
他们没钱雇佣你的男性同行
who cannot afford to hire your male counterparts.
我可以跟您保证
I can assure you
我有许多客户不是这样
I've had many clients who are neither of those things.
也许没有
Perhaps not,
但我打包票那些客户的案子
but I would wager that those clients had cases
因为太低级而不被其他地方受理
that were deemed too lowly to be taken on elsewhere.
您是说我是二流侦探
You were suggesting I'm regarded as somehow second rate.
我仅仅是指出 如果我们支持你
I'm merely pointing out that if we endorse you,
有可能会对协会声誉造成影响
it may have implications for the reputation at the society.
我完全能够理解 帕克夫人
I completely understand, Mrs Parker.
声誉一旦丢失 就很难再找回来了
Once a reputation is lost, it's so very hard to get back.
这就是为什么福布斯夫人你可以放心
Which is why you can rest assured, Mrs. Forbes,
我不会告诉任何人
that I will reveal to no one
您儿子离开海军的真正原因
the real reason your son left the Navy.
你怎么敢
How dare you!
伍德豪斯夫人 我向您保证
And you have my word, Mrs Woodhouse,
其他人不会从我这里听说
that it will not be from me
您已故丈夫欠下的赌债
that others hear of your late husband's gambling debts,
我相信这笔钱
which are I believe only exceeded
只比他欠坎宁镇妓院的钱少一些
by the money he owes to the brothels of Canning Town.
所以 结果怎么样
So how did it go?
翻译  黑猫
翻译  杨梅
翻译  门飘儿
翻译  凌大
翻译  飒白恬
校对&后期  飒白恬
斯嘉丽小姐和公爵
第二季 第二集
他在哪
Where is he?
这事不能外传 明白吗
This goes no further. Understood?
菲茨罗伊
Fitzroy.
起来
Get up.
我说了 起来
I said get up!
给我站稳 小伙子
You gonna steady 'em, lad?
看着我 菲茨罗伊
Look at me, Fitzroy.
看着我
Look at me.
有几根手指
How many fingers?
四根
Four.
不 是三根 是三根
No, it's three. It's three.
是三根
It's three.
是猜出来的吗
Is that a guess?
不
No.
我要你听仔细了 菲茨罗伊警探
I want you to listen carefully, Detective Fitzroy.
我不在乎你私下里做些什么
I don't give a damn what you do in your private life,
但你执勤的时候
but when you're on duty
你要以正常工作的样子准时出现
you turn up on time in a fit state to work.
现在我接到命令
Now I have been ordered to turn you
把你变成一个称职的警探
into a competent detective,
上帝保佑我
and God help me,
你要遵守规矩 照吩咐去做
you will toe the line and do as you're told.
明白了吗
Is that understood?
好极了
Good.
把你自己收拾干净
Clean yourself up man.
我可以跟她们说到面红耳赤
I could tell them till I was blue in the face
说我是凭本事吃饭的
that I'm hired on merit
但这有什么意义吗
but does it make a difference?
当然没有
Of course not.
没错 我确实是接了一些
Yes, I have taken on a few cases
没有达到现行率的案子
which are not paying the full going rate,
每个行业每个岗位的全国平均薪水
但将这归结于
but to suggest that it's because
我是女人 走投无路 是大错特错的
I'm a woman and somehow desperate is simply not true.
对吧 哈蒂
Is it, Hattie?
绝对是错的
Absolutely not true, at all.
- 但是 - 但是
- Although.. - Although?
但是 也许你不应该像那样惹恼我的姑妈
Although perhaps you should not have upset my aunt like that.
你不会希望与她为敌的
You do not want to make an enemy of her.
我之前就惹恼过你姑妈
I've suffered your Aunt's wrath before
但还是活了下来
and lived to tell the tale.
是的 但这次不一样
Yes, but this is different.
你当着文化协会那些夫人的面 让她下不来台
You embarrassed her front of her ladies of the Cultural Society,
那是她最好的朋友
her very best friends.
居然有她看得上的人 这倒是稀奇
I suppose it's nice to hear that she actually likes somebody.
不 她讨厌她们
Oh no, she loaths them,
但你必须提防着些 伊莱莎
but you must be on your guard, Eliza.
我姑妈有些位居高位的朋友们
My aunt does have friends in high places
记住我的话 她会伺机报复的
and mark my words: she will seek revenge.
这些位居高位的朋友中有戴高顶礼帽的吗
Do any of these friends in high places wear top hats?
亨利·斯嘉丽先生
私家侦探事务所
我不认识什么帕克夫人
I do not know a Mrs Parker
我是自愿来找你的
I have come to see you on my own volition.
好吧 那样的话
Well, in that case,
我能帮你些什么 斯沃布先生
how may I help you, Mr. Swab?
我是塑达保险公司的合伙人之一
I am a partner at Swab & Durstin,
公司总部位于霍本
an insurance firm based in Holborn.
塑达保险公司
伦敦霍本 约克路25号
我们为客户的生命和财产提供担保
We provide cover for the lives and properties of our clients,
保护他们远离生活所投来的明枪暗箭
protecting them from all the slings and arrows that life may throw.
每交一月的保险费
In return for a monthly fee,
他们会收到一份保单 这意味着...
they receive an insurance policy, which means..
我知道保险行业是如何运转的 斯沃布先生
I believe I understand how the insurance industry works, Mr Swab.
我能为你做些什么
What is it I can do for you?
昨晚 一件价值可观的物品
Last night, an item of considerable value
从我们其中一位投保人的手中被偷走了
was stolen from one of our policyholders.
一幅黑女巫蛾素描写生
A sketch of the alscalapha odorata or black witch moth
是1835年在加拉帕戈斯群岛上画的
drawn from life on the Galapagos Islands in 1835.
英国生物学家 进化论奠基人 曾历时五年进行环球航行
是在达尔文的航行中
During Darwin's voyage?
绝大多数加拉帕戈斯群岛的素描
Most of the Galapagos sketches
都是探险队里的艺术家康拉德·马丁绘制的
were drawn by the expedition's artist Conrad Martin,
但这幅是查尔斯·达尔文自己画的
but this was by Charles Darwin himself.
你可以想象
As you can imagine,
他年初去世以后
the value of his artwork
其艺术作品的价值在不断飙升
has soared since his death earlier this year,
因此我们将面临巨额赔付
and as such we are facing a significant payout.
先说清楚 我会收取全额佣金
Just to be clear, I will be charging the full going rate.
我没有想讨价还价
I would expect nothing less.
好极了
Good.
所以 告诉我 斯沃布先生
So tell me Mr. Swab.
这幅手稿是在哪被偷的
Where was this sketch stolen?
加瑞特自然科学博物馆
没有强行进入的迹象 也没有其他展品被盗
No sign of forced entry and no other exhibit stolen.
偷画人有着明确的目的
Whoever did this knew what they were looking for,
但为什么要费事把手从画框中拿走
but why go to the bother to take the sketch out of the frame?
这告诉了你什么
What does this tell you?
我问问题 是期望能有答案 菲茨罗伊警探
When I ask a question, I expect an answer, Detective Fitzroy.
是 长官 这个...
Yes, Sir, er...
你必须学着分析犯罪现场
You must learn to analyse a crime scene
这不仅仅是做笔记
and that involves more than just taking notes.
开始发挥主动性 小伙子
Start using your initiative, man.
他们没有带走相框意味着他们有充足的时间
The fact that they didn't take the frame means they had time.
这里没有发生惊慌的抢夺 长官
There was no panic to snatch and grab, Sir.
不错
Good.
这个蛾子叫什么来着
What was it called again, the moth?
黑女巫蛾
Alscalapha odorata.
发现于中美洲和南美洲
Found in central and south America,
一些土著文化认为
it's believed by some native cultures
它是死亡和毁灭的先兆
to be a harbinger of death and destruction.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
威灵顿督察
Inspector Wellington.
我认为这不是巧合
I take it this isn't a coincidence.
我被一家保险公司雇佣
I've been hired by the insurance company
调查达尔文手稿被盗一事
to investigate the theft of the Darwin sketch.
那他们认为我是在干什么
And what do they think I'm doing?
对你来说可能有些出乎意料 威灵顿督察
This may come as a surprise, Inspector Wellington,
但我和我的客户并没有说到你
but myself and my client did not discuss you.
我们调查完这里了
We're done here.
我们还有其他方面的调查
We have other lines of enquiry to pursue.
比如说
Such as?
我可以理解为你已经开始寻求我的帮助了
I must understand that you're asking for my help... already?
我只是客套客套
I'm merely making polite conversation.
尽管在这种情况下
Although given the circumstances,
我知道这可能被误解
I can see how that can be misconstrued.
毕竟 我们是在竞争 不是吗
After all, we are in competition, are we not?
博物馆的主人汉娜·加瑞特
The owner of the museum is Hannah Garret.
我在哪能找到她
Where would I find her?
这是另一个求助
Is this another request for help
还是我们依旧在客套
or are we still making polite conversation?
菲茨罗伊警探
Detective Fitzroy.
- 长官 你和她... - 闭嘴
- Sir, are you and her...? - No.
还有你的笔迹太潦草了
And your handwriting's illegible.
查尔斯·达尔文
恐怕我们今天要关门了
I'm afraid we are closed for the day.
我们早上会重开的
We'll reopen in the morning.
加瑞特女士
Miss Garret.
我是
Yes.
我是斯嘉丽小姐
Yes, my name is Miss Scarlet.
我是代表您的保险公司来的
I'm here on behalf of your insurance.
这是保险公司
It's standard practice for an insurance company
开展调查的标准流程
to carry out their investigation.
所以他们派了个女人过来
And they sent a woman?
什么意思
Meaning?
他们以为你更能获取我的信任
Meaning you would be better placed to gain my trust.
他们真的怀疑是我自己偷了那张手稿吗
Do they really suspect me of stealing the sketch myself?
加瑞特女士 他们派我来
I was sent, Miss Garret,
无非是因为我工作能力出色
for no other reason than that I'm good at my job,
我相信您也是
as I'm sure are you.
抱歉 我刚才有点无礼
I am sorry if I was rude.
我一个人经营博物馆 这差事特别消耗精力
I run the museum on my own and it is an all consuming venture.
让我疲惫
It can make me tired and..
还有点多疑
somewhat cynical.
跟我说说盗窃的事吧
So tell me about the theft.
手稿是夜里被盗的
It happened overnight.
没有强行闯入的迹象
There was no sign of a break in.
其他物品都没丢失
Nothing else was taken.
偷走手稿的人知道些实情
Whoever stole it knew the truth of the matter.
这里唯一值钱的东西就是那张手稿
The sketch was the only thing of real value here.
您是怎么得到这张达尔文的手稿的
How did you come to own the Darwin sketch?
几年前 我参加了一场他在皇家研究院的讲座
I attended a lecture he gave at the Royal Institution a few years ago.
我问了他一个有关黑女巫蛾
I asked him a question on the inherited characteristics
遗传特性的问题
of the Black Witch moth.
他非常谦虚
He was so modest.
他承认自己并不清楚
He admitted that he did not know.
但两周后我收到一份包裹还有一封信
But two weeks later, a package arrived with a letter
信里回答了我的问题
answering my question and..
还有他在加拉帕戈斯群岛画的速写
the sketch he'd drawn on the Galapagos.
托马斯特别生气
Thomas was furious.
托马斯
Thomas?
我丈夫 托马斯·达什伍德
My husband, Thomas Dashwood.
那位博物学家
The naturalist.
他很有名气
He has an impressive reputation.
从前他还会鼓励我对科学的热情
He used to encourage my passion for science,
但我的知识面越来越广
but as my knowledge grew,
他就变得不乐意了
so did his displeasure.
他想要的是学生 而非搭档
He wanted a pupil, not a partner.
所以我就开了博物馆
When I set up the museum,
他心里愤愤不平
he resented me for it.
那您现在使用的姓氏加瑞特 是父姓吗
But do you go by your... your maiden name of Garret?
您离婚了吗
You're divorced?
分居了
Separated.
我也想离婚 但是...
I would divorce, but..
离婚的成本很大 又是经济上又是...
the costs, both financial and otherwise..
这么说吧 那代价可不小
Let's just say it is a high price to pay.
我在哪里能见到您丈夫呢
So where would I find your husband?
小心点
Careful with that.
那一个就值你一年工资
Just one of those is worth more than your yearly wage.
抱歉 先生
Sorry, Sir.
有位女士来了
There's a lady here.
达什伍德先生
Mr. Dashwood?
我是伊莱莎·斯嘉丽
My name's Eliza Scarlet.
不管你是谁 都应该被邀请了再进来
Whoever you are, it is customary to wait until invited in.
抱歉 先生
Sorry, Sir.
我跟你说了多少次了 得开了那个女仆
How many times have I told you... that maid must be dismissed?
说了很多次了
Many times.
恕我冒昧打扰 达什伍德先生
Forgive the intrusion, Mr Dashwood,
但您能不能抽几分钟和我聊聊
but I hoped you might have a spare moment to talk.
我可没时间
I most certainly do not.
我马上要去皇家研究院做讲座
I'm giving a lecture at the Royal Institution
再说一遍 已经来不及了
and yet again I'm behind schedule.
这些拿出去 装马车上
Take those out to the carriage.
是有关您妻子的事
It concerns your wife.
我在寻找丢失的达尔文手稿
I'm attempting to recover the Darwin sketch.
那个女人
The sole intention of
唯一的目的就是羞辱我 仇视我
that woman is to humiliate and antagonise me.
我已经答复过警察了
I've already spoken to the police
不会再跟你费口舌
and will not explain myself to you,
天知道你是哪来的
whoever the hell you are.
要是想跟我聊我妻子的事 先找个律师来
If you want to speak to me about my wife, get yourself a lawyer.
你自己进来的
You saw yourself in.
那你也自己出去吧
You can see yourself out.
要说他平时不这样
I would say he's not normally like this,
那我肯定是在骗你
but that would be a lie.
你究竟是谁
Who are you exactly?
我是一名私家侦探
I'm a private investigator.
那你一定擅长找线索
So you're good with clues:
"夸张傲慢的风格"
"ostentatiously lofty in style"
由字母B开头
begins with the letter B.
玩字谜一天就过得很快
A word puzzle makes the day go faster.
字谜 还有杜松子酒
That and a bottle of schnapps.
要我帮您拿点什么吗
Can I get you something?
给我一副新肺吧
A new pair of lungs.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
请坐
Please sit.
我点烟的时候 别人都蔑视地看着我
Usually I receive a look of disdain when I light my pipe.
我从来都不知道
Never quite sure whether
究竟是因为我是女人还抽烟
it is the fact that I am a lady and smoking
还是因为我是生病的女人 还抽烟
or that I'm an unwell lady and smoking.
也可能仅仅因为我是德国人
It could be just that I'm German.
我在这里生活了五十年了
I've lived here for 50 years,
他们还把我当外人
yet still treated like a foreigner.
我打赌是三者都有吧
I would wager it's all three of those things.
一名女私家侦探 你真是个谜啊
A female private detective, now that is a puzzle.
我受保险公司雇佣
Well, I've been employed by the insurance company
调查加瑞特女士丢失的达尔文手稿
to investigate Miss Garret's Darwin sketch.
上次听到我儿媳的姓氏 还是达什伍德
Last I heard my daughter in law's name was still Dashwood.
但你要是想跟我儿子打交道
But if you wish to deal with my son,
你可得比刚才那样再强硬一点 姑娘
you will have to have more assertiveness than that, young lady.
他有点...
He is...
夸夸其谈
Bombastic.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
"夸张傲慢的风格"
"Ostentatiously lofty in style."
夸夸其谈
Bombastic.
Bombastic!
没错
Yes.
你在这里真好 斯嘉丽小姐
It is a good job you were here, Miss Scarlet.
你来完成吧
You finish it.
我儿子不喜欢我玩字谜上瘾
My son does not approve of my penchant for word play.
我觉得
I believe
我得去睡一觉
I should take a nap.
我请女仆送你出去
I will have my maid see you out.
抱歉
Sorry...
借过
Excuse me...
哈蒂
Hattie...
到底怎么了
what on earth is going on?
我不知道啊
I have no idea.
我路过 来打声招呼 就看见他们都在门外等着
I just popped in to say hello and I found them waiting outside.
他们一直说 "我找到了"
They keep saying they found it.
"我找到了"
They found it.
找到什么了
Found what?
全是假的
They're all fakes.
还用说吗
You don't say?
为什么都送到你办公室了
And why send them your office?
第五页下面有个广告
The advert on the bottom of page 5.
查尔斯·达尔文先生的黑女巫蛾手稿被盗
Stolen sketch of the black witch moth by Mr Charles Darwin.
安全送还者
A reward of £1000 is offered
将奖励一千英镑
for its safe return to
地址 伦敦埃博里路四十三号 伊莱莎·斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Eliza Scarlet of 43 Ebury Lane, London.
不是我投的广告
It wasn't me who placed it.
那张手稿价值五百英镑 但是赏金有两倍
The sketch is worth £500, yet this offer is twice that amount.
除非加瑞特女士对那张手稿有什么特殊的感情
Unless of course Miss Garret had a sentimental attachment to it.
或许值得投广告
Perhaps it was worth placing the advert.
我怀疑她能不能拿出来那笔钱
I doubt she has that kind of money.
就算她能
And even if she did,
为什么要用我的地址而不用博物馆的呢
why use my address and not the museum's?
她不是我的客户 保险公司才是
She's not my client. The insurance company are.
这本身就很稀奇
Which is curious in itself.
什么稀奇
What is?
保险公司选择雇你
That the insurance company would hire you.
肯定有什么原因吧
There must be a reason.
我工作能力出色 这就是原因
Because I'm good at my job, that's the reason.
我的意思是 他们可能怀疑加瑞特女士
All I meant is that they may suspect Miss Garret
所以雇佣女调查员来获取她的信任
and they hired a woman to gain her trust.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
我跟你一起
I'm coming with you.
我又要去哪里
Where am I going?
接待处
To reception.
我给一个人送了信 叫他来问话
I sent a message to someone we need to question.
他现在应该到了
He should have arrived by now.
伊莱莎 我可得提醒你
Eliza, do I need to remind you
这是我的办公室 不是你的
that this is my place of work, not yours?
到底是谁啊
Who is it anyway?
《警务新闻画报》的一名记者
A journalist at the Illustrated Police News.
巴兹尔·辛克莱尔
Basil Sinclair.
天哪 不要啊...
Please God, not him..
广告是匿名投放的
The advertisement was placed anonymously.
我们收到了一封信
We received a letter containing
上面只写了文案和发布日期
only the wording and the required date of publication.
是什么时候的事
When was this?
昨天晚邮送过来的
Yesterday, in the Evening Post,
六点之前一点
a little before 6:00 o'clock.
作为首席记者
As chief correspondent,
我的编辑斯迈兹先生来找过我
my editor, Mr Smythe, came to me.
他和我说 "巴兹尔
'Basil, ' he said,
没有人比你更了解达尔文先生了
'no one knows more of Mr Darwin than you do'.
你必须在警察有需要的时候帮助他们"
'You must help the police in their hour of need'.
所以广告是在抢劫发生前放好的吗
So the advert was placed before the robbery happened?
一想到我们受人尊敬的出版物
My heart soars at the prospect of
将成为如此引人入胜的谜团的中心
our esteemed publication being center stage of
我就感到雀跃不已
such an intriguing mystery.
辛克莱尔先生 这并不是谜团
It's not a mystery, Mr Sinclair.
这是一个偷窃案
it is a theft.
一切都会有完美合理的解释
There will be a perfectly rational explanation to all of this.
从伟大的查尔斯·达尔文那里偷来的艺术品
Stolen artwork from the great Charles Darwin himself.
伦敦警察厅被迫
Scotland Yard forced yet again
再次求助于女侦探
to turn to the lady detective.
斯嘉丽小姐不为伦敦警察厅工作
Miss Scarlet's not working for Scotland Yard.
我受雇于保险公司
I've been hired by the insurance company
他们希望能够进行自己的调查
who wished to carry out their own investigation.
亲爱的斯嘉丽小姐 你可能证明了我的观点
My dear Miss Scarlet, I feel you may have proved my point.
保险公司不就是因为对警察不信任
Is it not precisely due to a lack of faith in the police
才雇佣你的吗
that you are hired in the first place?
长官 应您要求
As requested, Sir,
我一直在细读过去的欺诈案卷宗
I've been perusing previous fraud cases.
然后我找到了那个艺术品商人的地址
I've secured an address for that art dealer.
你是说艺术品商人吗
Art dealer, you say?
那会是谁呢
And who might that be?
我来问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question
希望你能在回答之前仔细考虑一下
and I want you to think very carefully before you answer.
你是想让我的日子不好过吗
Are you trying to make my life difficult?
长官
Sir?
除了我以外 不要在任何人面前说出你的发现
Never show your findings in front of anyone else but me.
三思而后言
Think before you speak.
事实上 这样更好
In fact, better still,
除非我明确告诉你 否则不要开口
don't speak all unless I explicitly tell you to.
警探 你看起来有点热 你不舒服吗
You're looking rather warm detective. Are you unwell?
不是的 长官
No, Sir,
也许是现在的天气太温和了
perhaps it's the clement weather we're enjoying at present.
菲茨罗伊警探 听我的
Take my advice, Detective Fitzroy.
如果你想更好融入当地
If you wish to fit in here,
就不要再用"温和"这样的词语了
stop using words like clement.
好的 长官 抱歉 长官
Yes Sir, sorry Sir.
不要每五分钟就道歉一次
Stop apologising every five minutes.
通知车夫 我一会要去贝思纳尔格林
Alert my cab that I'll be going to Bethnal Green.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
菲茨罗伊警探
Detective Fitzroy.
去办事呀 伙计
Well get to it, man.
我可以给你一些建设性的批评吗
May I offer you some constructive criticism?
不要
No.
有时你可能需要平易近人一点
At times you might be a little more approachable,
尤其是对你的那些下属
particularly with those who are your subordinates.
如果给那个年轻人偶尔来句"干得好"
That nice young man looks like he could do
他会做得更好
with the occasional 'well done'.
除了你的女仆 你曾经做过任何人的上司吗
Have you ever been anyone's superior, apart from your housemaids?
没有 但是
No, but...
那就把这个建设性的批评留给你自己吧
Well, please keep your constructive criticism to yourself.
你要见的那个商人
This dealer you're going to see.
我猜他和黑市有某种联系
I'm assuming he's connected to the black market somehow.
或许曾经因为交易被盗艺术品而被定罪
Perhaps someone with previous convictions for trading stolen art.
看来我是对的
Good I'm right.
你的表情我都能读懂
There's no expression you possess that I cannot read.
威廉 我知道我们是竞争关系
William, I know we're in competition,
但是归根到底 我们都站在同一边
but when all is said and done we are on the same side.
法律的那边
The side of the law.
对你有利时 我们是站在一边的
We're on the same side when it suits you
当你说这些高尚的话时 我就不相信你了
and I don't trust you when you sound so noble.
投放广告的人
Whoever placed this advert
很清楚素描什么时候会被偷走
knew exactly when the sketch was going to be stolen.
我想回博物馆和加瑞特女士再谈一次
I'd like to go back to the museum and speak to Miss Garret again,
我想你也会的
and I suspect you would too.
如果我们能共享情报的话 就能节省时间
We'd save ourselves time if we shared our resources.
你去和商人谈
You speak to this dealer.
我去博物馆
I'll go to the museum and
稍后见面再分享我们的情报
we'll meet up later to share our findings.
不需要
No.
行吧
Very well.
或许我会和我们的记者朋友合作
Then perhaps I'll team up with our journalist friend
和他分享我的发现
and share my observations with him.
不仅仅是这个案子 还有其他故事
And not just about the case, but wider stories too,
比如你有一次在执勤时喝醉了 还丢了搜查令
like the time you were drunk on duty and lost your warrant card.
你到底是怎么知道这些事的
How the hell do you find these things out?
人们告诉我的
People speak to me.
这就是我身为女人 平易近人的方式
It's my woman's approachable manner.
好吧
Fine.
加瑞特自然科学博物馆
可笑至极
Ridiculous.
我为什么要做那样的事
Why would I do such a thing?
为了向保险公司索赔
To claim the money from the insurance
来支撑你濒临倒闭的生意
and prop up your failing business.
它不会倒闭
It's NOT failing!
这里的屋顶漏水
There are leaks in the roof,
墙壁油漆脱落
paint peeling from the walls
展品也破碎了
and exhibits falling to pieces.
你没法经营这个地方
You cannot afford to run this place,
但你依然固执地不想卖掉它
but you're too stubborn to sell it.
我会揭露你的真面目
I will expose you for what you are.
你就是个小偷
A thief!
立刻滚出去
Get out NOW!
加瑞特自然科学博物馆
我经营合法的艺术品 有完整的出处记录
I deal in legitimate works of art sold with full provenance.
督察 您这样的问法让我感到被侮辱了
In fact Inspector, I am insulted that you would even ask.
很抱歉 吉布森先生
My apologies, Mr Gibson.
我想 有十二次倒卖赃物和三次诈骗前科的人
I assume that man with 12 convictions for handling stolen goods
可能是合适的谈话对象
and three for fraud might be the right person to talk to.
那都是过去的事了
That was all in my past.
我已经洗心革面了
I'm a changed man.
你最后一次被定罪是在六周前
Your last conviction was six weeks ago.
所以也许你可以
So perhaps you can...
你刚刚说什么来着
what was your phrase?
"合法的艺术品 有完整的出处记录"
'Legitimate works of art with full provenance'..
是这样的
They are.
那样的话 我得核实一下情况是否属实
In that case I shall have to check that is so.
在此期间 你必须被拘留
You'll have to be kept in custody in the meantime.
我现在想了想 有个人浮现在我的脑海里
Now I think about it, there is one person comes to mind.
我想应该是吧
I thought there might be.
这是你想要的那个人
Yeah, this is the man you want.
他经营那些特别的艺术品
He deals in specialist works of art.
比如被盗的那件
Like the one that was stolen.
我不知道他的真名 人们都这样称呼他
I don't know his real name, that's what they call him.
伯爵
The Count?
你为什么跟踪我
Why are you following me?
我没有跟踪你
I wasn't following you.
我只是迷路了
I lost my way.
在酒馆里你就一直看着我
You were watching me in the tavern.
告诉我你是谁
Tell me who you are
否则我就一枪毙了你
or I will shoot you in the head.
你不会的
No, you will not.
为什么
Why is that then?
因为有警察在你身后
Because there's a police officer standing behind you.
你觉得我是个傻子吗
Do you think I'm an idiot?
你是
Yes.
既然你问了
Since you ask.
加瑞特女士是不是想把达尔文的手稿卖给你
Was Miss Garret trying to sell you the Darwin sketch?
我对你说的手稿一无所知
I know nothing of this sketch you speak of,
但我建议你们小心行事
but I suggest you tread very carefully.
这是为什么
And why is that exactly?
因为我是贝桑斯基家族的
Because I'm a Basinski.
我的家族是匈牙利贵族中最古老的家族之一
My family is one of the oldest dynasties in Hungarian nobility.
我应该深受震撼吗
Am I supposed to be impressed?
只是警告你我有有势力的朋友
Merely warning you that I have influential friends.
我建议你好好回答问题
I suggest you answer the question
否则威灵顿督察
or Inspector Wellington here
会把你的腿当做柴火烧掉
will take your leg and use it for firewood.
加瑞特女士不是想卖掉
No, Miss Garret was not selling.
她想买回 但是我告诉她我没有那件艺术品
She was trying to buy, but I told her I did not have it.
那次谈话似乎花了很长时间
That conversation seemed to take an awfully long time.
因为她一开始不相信我
That is because she did not believe me at first.
她以为我在讨价还价
She thought I was bargaining.
她没有钱 只有博物馆的几件展品
She had no money to offer, only a few exhibits from the museum.
基本上毫无价值
Worthless, mostly.
她感到绝望
The woman is desperate,
所以我说 如果有什么消息我会告诉她的
so I told her if I heard anything I will let her know.
那你有听说什么吗
And have you heard anything?
什么都没有
Not a word.
这里越来越冷了
Getting rather chilly in here.
你觉得呢 斯嘉丽小姐
Don't you agree, Miss Scarlet?
我想可能需要加点柴火
I think perhaps the fire might need a little help.
好吧
Very well.
我听说过一两件事
I have heard one or two things.
- 关于加瑞特女士吗 - 是关于她丈夫
- About Miss Garret? - About her husband.
人们说他出价极高 从不问任何问题
They say he pays extremely well, no questions asked.
你想找到那幅素描
You want to find that sketch.
我知道该去哪里找
I know where I would be looking.
我先去找执法官
I'm going to a magistrate first thing...
申请搜查令去搜查达什伍德的房子
get a warrant to search Dashwood's house.
好 我们在那里会合
Good. I'll meet you there.
你就不能别惹我生气吗
It's difficult enough without any added irritation.
我怎么惹你生气了
So I'm an irritation now, am I?
我的意思是 让事情简单点更好
I really mean it's better to keep things simple.
你就等我联系你
You'll wait for me to contact you
知会你调查进展
with an update on how the search went..
对这事 我最后再说一句
and that is my final word on the matter.
我会找到手稿 并且我保证
I'll find the sketch, then I will make sure
我会告诉你的雇主 你参与了调查
that your employers know your part in the investigation.
你还是能拿到报酬
You'll still receive your fee,
除非你为了自我价值非要掺和
unless this is more about your ego.
你真要讨论自我的事情吗
Do you really wish to talk about ego?
长官
Sir...
有位荷兰绅士 洛曼先生
There's a Dutch gentleman, a Mr Lohman,
在您办公室等您
waiting for you in your office.
他希望聊聊达尔文手稿案
He'd like to discuss the Darwin case.
洛曼先生
Mr. Lohman.
我来自沃霍保险
From Woban and Holst,
被盗画作由我司承保
the company who insured the stolen picture.
不对 承保公司是塑达保险
No, the insurance firm is Swab and Durstin.
请看
Here..
其中一位合伙人来见过我
See, I was visited by one of the partners.
我从未听说过这个公司
I have never heard of such a company.
描述一下这人的外貌
Describe the man you met.
个子较小 威尔士口音 高顶帽
Small in stature, Welsh accent, top hat,
前额有胎记
and he had a slight birthmark on his forehead.
此人不是我司员工
Whoever he is, he does not work for my company.
那又是谁雇在我
Well, if he didn't hire me, then who did?
塑达保险公司
伦敦霍本 约克路25号
为什么这人要给你
Why would this man give you a card
不存在的公司的名片呢
for a business that does not exist?
这说不通啊
It does not make any sense.
哈蒂 很高兴见到你
Hattie, it's always nice to see you,
但你不能老这样突然出现
but you really cannot keep popping in like this.
名片格外精致
It's a very nice card to boot.
这个粗体浮雕很妙
It's subtle, that bold embossing.
家父生前从事印刷业
My father was in the ink business
而且对于精心选择的字体
and there was nothing that comes close to my passion
我向来爱不释手
than a well chosen font.
这么说 你或许能帮上忙
Oh well, then perhaps you can help me.
我想知道是谁定制了这些名片
I need to find out who ordered these cards.
哈蒂
Hattie?
你希望我来帮忙
You want me to help you?
就像助理一样
I mean like an assistant?
是的 如果你愿意
Yes, if you like.
我会带你走遍全城文印店 伊莱莎
I will take you to every stationer's in town, Eliza
路上我会向你介绍十二种印刷字体
and on the way I shall explain the twelve types of calligraphy.
我已经迫不及待了
I can hardly wait.
怎么样
Well?
她情况如何
What's the matter with her?
先生
Sir...
什么事
What is it now?
你们到底要干嘛
What the hell is this?
我们有搜查令 先生
We have a warrant to search these premises, sir.
家母重病在床 你们却破门而入
My mother is extremely ill and you come marching in...
是您的女仆放我们进来的
We were let in by your maid.
跟此案有关的事我已和盘托出
I have said all I have to say on this matter.
你们没有正当理由搜查
You've no just cause to be here.
达什伍德先生 请您冷静
Mr Dashwood I would request that you control your temper, sir.
不好
Right!
菲茨罗伊 菲茨罗伊
Fitzroy... Fitzroy!
你们到底在搞什么
What on Earth is going on here?
威灵顿 情况如何
Ah, Wellington. How are we?
一切都好 谢谢您 长官
Fine, thank you, Sir.
小菲茨罗伊表现如何
How's young Fitzroy getting on?
长官 他其实...
Actually, Sir, he's uh..
他做得不错
he's doing very well.
很好
Glad to hear it.
总监让我看看他 他现在在吗
Commissioner asked me to check in on him. Is he around?
现在不在 先生
Not at the moment, Sir.
他出外勤 协助我处理达尔文手稿案
He is out assisting me on the Darwin investigation.
他的进步 你还满意吧
You're happy with his progress, yes?
任重道远 但确实满意
He still has a lot to learn, but yes..
那就好 我会转告他父亲
Glad to hear it. I'll let his father know.
再接再厉
Keep up the good work.
我是斯嘉丽小姐的顾问
I am acting as consultant
协助进行一项重要调查
to Miss Scarlet's extremely important investigation.
凭借我在文印行业丰富的专业知识
Given my considerable expertise in the business of stationary,
本人绝非自吹自擂
I do not boast when I say that
本人对以下方面造诣颇深
I have an encyclopedic knowledge of embossing,
浮雕印刷 字体 字距
calligraphy, kerning,
以及名片印刷的重中之重
and the jewel in the crown of any calling card -
字形
the font.
- 我的最爱是... - 帕克小姐
- My particular favour... - Miss Parker.
这张名片是在此印制的吗
Was this card made on these premises?
请您稍等
One moment, please..
哈蒂 能否请你交谈时更为言简意赅
Hattie, may I ask you be more economical with your conversation?
-言简意赅 - 安静
- Economical? - Keep quiet!
我们上周售出一本
We sold a book last week.
你还记得买方是谁吗
Do you remember who to?
雷金纳德·布斯先生
Mr Reginald Booth.
R·布斯律师
宣誓公证人
达什伍德
我是威灵顿督察 听说你希望和我谈谈
I'm Inspector Wellington. I understand you wish to speak with me.
我代表客户达什伍德家族到访
I am here on behalf of my clients, the Dashwood family.
我是他们的法律顾问
I am their legal counsel and as such
托马斯·达什伍德先生让我转达
Mr Thomas Dashwood has asked me to relay
其母过世的消息
the sad news of the passing of his mother.
节哀顺变
My condolences.
达什伍德老夫人久病在床
Mrs Dashwood has been ill for some time
她的过世并不让人意外
so it is not completely unexpected,
但对其子仍是沉重的打击
but still a terrible blow to her son.
您可以想象 他悲伤难耐
As you can imagine, he is stricken with grief
因此要求您日后莫再骚扰他
and requests that you desist from harassing him any further.
是吗
Does he now?
他希望我转告您 他家财颇丰
He has asked me to point out that he is a man of wealth
能全额负担起打官司的费用
who could fund the most thorough of legal challenges.
我建议 日后沟通直接通过我进行
I would advise that any future communications come directly through myself.
R. Booth律师
霍本 维斯特里街28号
祝您日安 先生
I bid you a good day, Sir.
你有威尔士口音 布斯先生
So the Welsh accent I detect, Mr Booth.
有何相干
I fail to see the relevance.
室内着帽 不合规矩吧
Is it not customary to remove one's hat when indoors?
我行程繁忙
I am a busy man
另有邀约要赴 督察先生
with many other appointments to attend, Inspector.
你在冒犯我
You offend me, sir.
请脱帽
Kindly take it off.
荒谬至极
This is quite ridiculous.
我的马车在外面侯着
My car is waiting outside.
要么你自己脱帽
Either you take off your hat
要么我帮你脱
or I'll take it off for you.
我有位同事 想必你认识
I believe you know, an associate of mine.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
那么
Well.
看来你这次的身份是真的
Seems you are who you claim to be.
雷金纳德·布斯律师
Mr Reginald Booth, solicitor,
维斯特里街二十八号
of 28 Westerly Row.
说吧 为何要假扮斯沃布先生
So tell me why you were impersonating a Mr. Swab
一位虚构保险公司的雇员
who works for a bogus insurance fund.
我否认您的指控
I deny any such accusation
此外 我要知道自己是否被批捕
and furthermore would ask if I am under arrest.
若情况属实 您未尽告知之职
If so, you have failed to mention it.
布斯先生 你随时可以离去
You're free to go at any time,Mr Booth,
我也随时可以去法律学会
just as I am free to go to the Law Society
举报你欺诈
and report you for fraud.
我为达什伍德家族工作了很多年
I have worked for the Dashwood family for some years,
最开始服务于达什伍德先生的父亲
at first for Mr. Dashwood's late father,
随后服务于达什伍德先生
then latterly for Mr. Dashwood himself.
我勤勉 顺从 并以此取酬
I am paid for my diligence and compliance.
你是说你的所作所为是有人指使
You mean you do what you're told?
是的 我为客户尽心尽力
I do my best for my clients, yes.
托马斯·达什伍德先生对斯嘉丽小姐有何兴趣
And what interest did Thomas Dashwood have in Miss Scarlet?
让我去见她的 并非托马斯·达什伍德先生
It was not Thomas Dashwood who told me to visit her.
卡尔纳克神庙
The Temple of Karnak...
警务新闻画报
女侦探侦破幽灵案
伊莱莎·斯嘉丽侦破案件
所以达什伍德老夫人曾是勇敢的探险家
So Mrs Dashwood was an intrepid explorer.
但被排斥在历史书之外
But very much left out of the history books.
我做了调查 这个考古队只有她一名女性
I've done some research and there's no mention of her among the
但历史书里从未提及她
otherwise male archaeology team.
律师说 她家里安排她嫁给一个英国富人
The lawyer said when her family married her off to a rich,
对方大她许多
much older English husband.
并且坚持让她待在家里 恪守妇道
he insisted that she stay at home and behave more appropriately.
我能理解她为什么喜欢你
I can see why she liked you.
等她丈夫去世
Then when her husband died,
她对自然科学重燃热情
she hoped to rekindle her passion for the natural sciences.
但她儿子与其父完全一样
Her son was a chip off the old block.
不愿让她影响到他自己的事业
He didn't want her tainting his own career.
他对妻子也是如此
Something he tried to inflict on his wife, too.
如果是达什伍德老夫人
If Mrs Dashwood is the one
把记者辛克莱尔卷进来的
that got that journalist Sinclair involved,
那她显然是想炮制一篇新闻报道
then she clearly wanted to create a story.
但我不太能理解她的计划
And yet, I can't quite work out her plan.
是个谜题
It's a puzzle.
当然是
It certainly is.
不 我的意思是 有场解谜游戏
No, I mean, there's a puzzle.
卡尔纳克王表的发现
The discovery of the Karnak King List
因那场比赛而闻名
was famous for the race to find it.
比赛涉及破译地图 象形文字谜语
It involved decyphering maps, hieroglyphic riddles..
达什伍德老夫人非常喜爱猜谜
How Mrs Dashwood loved to riddle.
我初见她时 她就在玩填字游戏
When I met her she was trying to compete a word game.
我还给了她提示
I helped with a clue.
或许这位难以捉摸的达什伍德老夫人
Maybe the enigmatic Mrs Dashwood
还没解完谜题就去世了
died before her puzzle came to fruition.
夜深了 我们明早再接着查吧
It's late, we should pick this up in the morning.
我送你回家
I'll see you home.
七字谜语
Seven letter puzzle.
是变位词吗
Anagram?
塑达保险公司
没错
Exactly.
我想我知道达尔文手稿在哪了
I think I know where the Darwin sketch is.
加瑞特自然科学博物馆
您岳母很喜欢您
Am I right in thinking your
我说得对吗 加瑞特女士
mother-in-law is fond of you, Miss Garret?
她是那个家里
She was the only one in that family
唯一对我好的人
who ever treated me with kindness.
她来过这儿很多次
She came here many times,
惹得她儿子不悦
much to the annoyance of her son.
有没有这种可能
Is it possible that on one of those visits,
她在一次探访中拿了备用钥匙
she could have taken a spare set of keys?
您的意思是
Are you suggesting that
是我岳母偷走了画吗
it was my mother-in-law who had it stolen from me?
没错 但她是善意的
We are, but with a good intention.
我相信这并不是关于善意的故事
I trust this is not a tale of kindness.
一篇关于团结和怜悯的报道
A story of solidarity and compassion
可不好卖
is rather a difficult sell.
还是让斯嘉丽小姐来解释吧 辛克莱尔先生
Well, shall we just give Miss Scarlet a moment to explain, Mr Sinclair.
达什伍德老夫人的律师
Mrs Dashwood's lawyer hired me
是以假的保险公司之名来雇我的
using the name of a bogus insurance company.
塑达保险
Swab & Durstin.
达什伍德老夫人对翻译和文字游戏情有独钟
Mrs Dashwood had a fondness for translation and word play.
"塑达"这个名字其实指的是
The name Swab and Dustin is an anagram
"达尔文塑像"
for 'Darwin's bust'.
出自《圣经·诗篇》
我的福杯满溢
My cup runneth over.
达什伍德夫人希望
Mrs Dashwood hoped this story
这篇报道能够为博物馆带来关注
would generate publicity for the museum
给你带来客源
to bring in the crowds for you.
这是一个女性试图在男权世界里有所作为的故事
It's the story of a woman trying to make it in a man's world,
一名女侦探一路调查她
a female detective investigating her a long way,
这位颇有才华的女性
and a cunning trail
留下了巧妙的痕迹
laid by a brilliant lady
而她此生却不能一展才华
who wasn't allowed to be brilliant in life.
您岳母是想帮您 加瑞特女士
Your mother in law wanted to help you, Miss Garret.
我不知道该说什么
I do not know what to say.
加瑞特女士 您无需说什么
You need find no words, Miss Garret.
因为我巴兹尔·辛克莱尔会帮您写出来的
for Basil Sinclair shall find them for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
荣幸之至
It's my pleasure.
加瑞特自然科学博物馆
这篇报道刊登出来之后
When the story is published
加瑞特女士的事业定会腾飞
Miss Garret will find business booming.
门庭若市
They'll be queuing out the door.
这场景足以气煞她丈夫
Much to her husband's dismay.
威廉 虽然我不想承认 但你是对的
William, I hate to admit it, but you were right.
我能接到这个案子 只是因为我是女性
It was only because I'm a woman that I got the case.
所以呢
So?
我希望自己被雇佣是因为我的专业能力
So I want to be hired for being good at what I do,
而非身为女性
not because I wear a bonnet.
伊莱莎 身为女性是你无法回避的事实
Eliza, there is no escaping that you are a woman,
正如身为男性是我无法回避的事实
just like there was no escaping that I'm a man.
我还是苏格兰人
I'm also Scottish,
年仅三十
young enough to say that I'm still only 30,
颇明事理
old enough to know better
而这些都可以转化为有利条件
and these are all things that I use to my advantage when it suits.
你要怎么把苏格兰人的身份转化为有利条件
How do you use being Scottish to your advantage?
反正不是喝得醉醺醺的苏格兰人
That's nothing like a drunken Scott to deceive
能在牌桌上骗过自负的笨蛋
an overconfident idiot at the poker table.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is,
充分利用你的资源
use what you have to your advantage,
和其他人一样
just like anyone else does.
男女有别
Man or woman.
就这么简单 不必强求
It's no more complex than that, so do not make it so.
好了 我得走了
Right, I must leave.
我可不想被辛克莱尔先生缠上
I don't want to be stuck with Mr Sinclair.
他的行为举止
There is something in his manner
总让我有种想揍他的冲动
that gives me the urge to punch him.
督察
Inspector...
能麻烦您捎我一程吗
Might I trouble you for a ride back to the office?
我在路上可以跟您重述一下这个故事
And on the way I can regale you with my retelling of this
让您开心哦
rather delicious story.
我和主治医生聊过了
I spoke with your doctor.
他说你没事
He said you'll be fine.
他还说你很幸运
He also said you were lucky.
你的心脏一度紊乱到极其危险的地步
Your heart rate was dangerously erratic.
要是再发作一次 可能会要你的命
It could kill you if it happens again.
我没告诉他我对发病诱因的猜测
I didn't tell him my suspicions as to what may have caused it.
在嫌疑人面前倒下是不可饶恕的 长官
Collapsing in front of a suspect was unforgivable, Sir.
您会把我的表现报告给门罗警司吧
I assume you're going to inform Superintendent Munro of my behavior?
我为何要这么做
And why would I do that?
无论你做什么 承担责任的是我
Anything that you do, it's me who has to answer for it,
如履薄冰的是我
it's me whose head is on the block.
我父亲为了让我成才
In his quest to make something of his son,
把我送去一连串的机构培养
my father has sought help in a long line of institutions.
先是他原来的寄宿学校 然后是他挚爱的陆军学校
His old boarding school and then his beloved Sandhurst
我甚至在海军待了一段时间
and even a short spell in the Navy.
情况如何
How did they fare?
我遭到无休止的霸凌
I was relentlessly bullied
但这只是加深了我父亲的偏见
and they only served to cement my father's opinion
认为我是家族的耻辱
that I am an embarrassment to our family.
我猜警局是他最后的希望
And the police force is, unfortunately for me, his last hope.
父亲看不起自己 这实在难以承受
It is a burden indeed to know that your own father despises you.
于是
and..
鸦片成了一种慰藉
the opium has gone some way, providing me with some relief.
我是济贫院长大的 每天挨的是拳打脚踢
All I had growing up was a daily beating in the workhouse.
我们都有伤疤 菲茨罗伊
We all have our scars, Fitzroy.
你要想求安慰 就别指望我
If it's sympathy or after, don't look to me.
我跟过那么多指挥官
Of all the men whose command I have been under,
您是最宽容的一个
you... you are the most decent man of all of them
所以长官 我定会竭尽全力 让您以我为豪的
and that is why I will do whatever it takes to make you proud of me, Sir.
你有什么想法
So what do you suggest?
让我担任行政职责吧 长官 我会做好的
Put me on administration duty, Sir, I'd be good at that.
我知道我可以成为像样的警探
I know I can be a decent detective.
只是需要时间学习基础
I just need some time to learn the basics.
那就决定了
Well, that's a decision then.
你身体恢复后 按时报道
You come on time ready to work
一切从头开始
and we'll take it from there.
谢谢长官 我不会让您失望的
Thank you, Sir. I will not let you down.
还有件事 警探
There is one more thing, Detective.
什么事 长官
Yes, Sir?
把你那该死的头发剪短
Get that bloody hair cut.
遵命 长官
Consider it done, Sir.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
帕克夫人 真是意外啊
Mrs Parker, what a nice surprise.
我从未在姐妹面前受过如此凌辱
Never have I been so humiliated in front of my ladies.
你的所作所为不可饶恕
What you did was unforgivable.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry for it.
我无意羞辱您
My intention was not to humiliate you.
你的指控太可恨了
And the accusations you made - abhorrent!
都是基于事实的指控
Accusations based on truth.
我会发动我所有的影响力
I will use every ounce of my influence
摧毁你 还有你的小小私家侦探事业
to destroy you and your little private investigation business.
我会极尽办法惩罚你
I will have my retribution to my full satisfaction
毁掉你 斯嘉丽小姐
and see you ruined, Miss Scarlet.
自你走后 我脑中就有过这类似的想法
These and other thoughts ran through my head after you left.
那你现在不这么想了吗
So you do not think them now?
我做了点调查
I did a little research of my own.
看上去 你的指控都是...
It appears your accusations were..
正确的
correct.
所以
So.
鉴于你已经证明了自己的智谋
Given you have proven your resourcefulness.
我想另外委托你一件事
I wish to engage you in another matter.
这些绅士
These are the gentlemen I have selected
是我给我侄女挑的结婚人选
as potential husbands for my niece.
她已经不小了
As yet she has had no offers of marriage
却还没有缔结婚约
and is not getting any younger.
事实上
In fact,
我想她和你年纪相仿 斯嘉丽小姐
I believe she's the exact same age as you, Miss Scarlet.
我要拿到每个候选人的完整档案
So, I would like a complete dossier on each candidate
这样我就能根据匹配度做选择了
and then I can make my choice as to their suitability.
您想雇佣我
You wish to hire me?
日安
Good day.
我糊涂了 帕克夫人
I'm confused, Mrs Parker.
您曾说 我的客户或绝望或贫穷
You declared my clients to be either desperate or impoverished,
付不起标准酬金
unable to pay the going rate,
但您现在却要做我的客户
yet you wish to be a client now.
我可以保证 我跟这两样都不沾边
I can assure you I am neither of those things
我愿意付全款
and I am willing to pay the full fee.
为什么找我
Why me?
为什么不去找男侦探
Why not go to one of my male counterparts?
我找你 不找别人 有一个绝妙的理由
There is a very good reason I came to you and no one else.
你是我认识的唯一一名私家侦探
You are the only private investigator I know
就这么简单
and it is no more complex than that.
"不必强求 伊莱莎"
'Do not make it so, Eliza'?
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.vip
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现